The most complex problems in our time
现如今，只要有梦想，
can be solved with simple techniques, if we are able to dream.
就可以用最简单的手段解决最复杂的问题。
As a child, I discovered that creativity is the key
在孩童时期，我发现让梦想照进现实的关键，
to cross from dreams to reality.
在于创造力。
I learned this from my grandmother, Dr. Ruth Tichauer,
我是从我的外祖母，Ruth Tichauer博士那里学到的，
a Jewish refugee that settled in the heart of the Andes.
她是居住在安第斯山脉深处的一位犹太难民。
That is how I grew up:
在我成长的一路上，
encouraged to see beyond any limitation.
外祖母总是鼓励我超越自己的极限。
So part of my education included helping her in remote, indigenous communities.
我的一部分教育来自于在遥远的当地部落帮她做事的经历。
I cherish those memories,
我非常珍惜这些经历，
because they helped me to understand life outside the city,
因为它们帮我了解了城市以外的生活，
a life with a lot of possibilities,
那种生活有无限可能，
without barriers, as language or culture.
没有语言或文化的障碍。
During those trips, my grandmother used to recite a Kipling poem:
在那些旅途当中，外祖母曾经背过吉普林的一首诗：
"Something hidden. Go and find it.
“出发吧，去寻觅隐藏的宝藏。
Go and look behind the Mountains.
去山川背后寻找。
Something lost behind the mountains.
那些宝藏遗失在山川背后，
Lost and waiting for you. Go!"
正在等待你的发掘。出发吧！”
In the coming years, I became a medical student.
后来几年，我去了医学院读书。
One of every hundred children born worldwide has some kind of heart disease.
我得知，世界上每一百个新生儿中就会有一个患有某种心脏疾病。
There's a part of this problem I think I can solve --
我认为这是个我有能力去帮助治愈的疾病——
the part of this problem I have spent my life working on.
事实上，我一生都致力于这项研究。
The problem starts during pregnancy.
这个疾病产生于怀孕期间。
The fetus needs to survive inside the mother.
胎儿是否能够在母亲腹中存活，
Survival depends on communication
取决于血液在
between the systemic and the pulmonary blood.
体循环与肺循环间的交换。
At the moment of birth,
胎儿出生时，
this communication needs to stop.
这一交换必须停止。
If it doesn't close, the baby has a hole in the heart.
如果未能停止，婴儿就会出现先天性心脏缺损。
It is caused by prematurity and genetic conditions.
这个问题多由早产及遗传因素引发。
But what we know today
但如今我们发现，
is that a lack of oxygen is also one of the causes.
缺氧也会引发这一疾病。
As you can see in the chart,
在图中可以看到，
the frequency of this kind of hole
随着海拔的增高，
dramatically increases with altitude.
这种病出现的频率也大幅增加。
Video: (Baby crying)
视频：（婴儿哭声）
When you look at patients with this condition,
先天性心脏缺损的患者
they seem desperate to breathe.
难以正常呼吸。
To close the hole, major surgery used to be the only solution.
过去，我们只能通过大手术来修复这一缺损。
One night, my friend Malte, were camping in the Amazon region.
有一天，我和我朋友Malte在亚马逊流域露营。
The only thing that would not burn in the fire was a green avocado branch.
我们发现唯一不能被火点燃的东西是绿鳄梨的树枝。
Then came a moment of inspiration.
这时我们有了一个灵感。
So we used the branch as a mold for our first invention.
我们利用这种枝条设计出了一个器材雏形。
The holes in children's hearts can be closed with it.
它可以修补儿童心脏上的缺损。
A coil is a piece of wire wrapped onto itself.
这是一种螺旋体缠绕的结构。
It maybe doesn't look so fancy to you now,
也许对你们而言这并不稀奇，
but that was our first successful attempt to create a device for this major problem.
但它却是我们修补心脏的首次成功尝试。
In this video, we can see how a very tiny catheter
这个视频演示了微型导管将螺旋体
takes the coil to the heart.
植入心脏的过程。
The coil then closes the hole.
之后，螺旋体修补了漏洞。
After that moment of inspiration,
经由这一灵感启发，
there came a very long time of effort
我们通过相当长时间的努力，
developing a prototype.
研发出了一种器材原型。
In vitro and in vivo studies took thousands of hours of work in the lab.
我们在实验室里进行了上千小时的体外实验及研究。
The coil, if it works, can save lives.
这种螺旋体一旦成功植入，就能挽救生命。
I returned from Germany to Bolivia,
我从德国返回波利尼亚，
thinking that wherever we go,
想着无论我们去哪，
we have the opportunity to make a difference.
都有机会实现重大突破。
With my wife and partner, Dr. Alexandra Heath,
我和我妻子，也是我的合作伙伴Alexandra Heath博士
we started to see patients.
一起开始接诊。
After successfully treating patients with our coil,
在成功地用螺旋体治愈患者后，
we felt really enthusiastic.
我们感到非常激动。
But we live in a place that is 12,000 feet high.
但我们住在海拔3600多米的地方。
And,
而且，
the patients there need a special device to solve their heart condition.
那里的病人们需要一种特别的器材来解决他们的心脏问题。
The hole in altitude patients is different,
高海拔地区病人的心脏缺损不同于其他地区，
because the orifice between the arteries is larger.
因为他们的动脉孔径更大。
Most patients cannot afford to be treated on time,
绝大多数患者因得不到及时治疗，
and they die.
最终不幸去世。
The first coil could successfully treat
我们的第一代螺旋体只能成功救治
only half of the patients in Bolivia.
玻利维亚一半的患者。
The search started again.
于是我们又从零开始
We went back to the drawing board.
寻找新的材料。
After many trials,
多次试验无果后，
and with the help of my grandmother's indigenous friends in the mountains,
我在外祖母在山区的原住民朋友的帮助下，
we obtained a new device.
获得了一种新的器材。
For centuries, indigenous women told stories by weaving complex patterns on looms,
几个世纪以来，原住民妇女在织布机上织出了各种复杂的图案，
and an unexpected skill helped us for the new device.
我们从这种传统织布工艺上得出灵感。
We take this traditional method of weaving
我们用这种纺织方法
and make a design made by a smart material
加工出了一种智能材料，
that records shape.
具有形状记忆的特性。
It seems this time,
看起来这次，
the weaving allows us to create a seamless device
织布技术似乎帮我们造出了一种无缝器材，
that doesn't rust
它不会生锈，
because it's made of only one piece.
因为它是一体化的，没有接缝。
It can change by itself into very complex structures
它可以通过一种花费了数十年才研发出的方法
by a procedure that took decades to develop.
改变自身形状，变成极为复杂的结构。
As you can see, the device enters the body
我们可以看到，这种器材无需
through the natural channels.
大型切口就可以进入人体。
Doctors have only to close the catheter through the hole.
医生只需要在穿过心脏缺损的部分后关闭导管。
Our device expands, places itself
我们的这种器材会自动膨大并找准位置，
and closes the hole.
紧接着修复心脏缺损。
We have this beautiful delivery system that is so simple to use
这种放置方式极为简单，
because it works by itself.
因为它可以自动完成，
No open surgery was necessary.
我们不再需要创伤性手术。
(Applause)
（掌声）
As doctors, we fight with diseases
我们医生与疾病抗争，
that take a long time and effort to heal -- if they do.
有的疾病就算能治愈，也需要花费很长时间、很多努力。
This is the child from before,
这是之前那个患儿
after the procedure.
手术后的影像资料，
As you can see --
我们可以看到——
(Applause)
（掌声）
As you can see, once the device is in place,
我们可以看到，这种器材一旦放入，
the patient is 100 percent healed.
患者的治愈率就可以达到100%。
From start to finish,
从手术开始到结束，
the whole procedure takes only 30 minutes.
只需要短短30分钟。
That's very rewarding from the medical and human point of view.
这从医疗及普通人的角度来说都非常令人振奋。
We are so proud that some of our former patients
我们可以骄傲地说，之前的一些患者现在也成为了
are part of our team --
我们团队的一员——
a team, thanks to added close interaction with patients that work with us.
非常感谢患者与我们的密切合作。
Together, we have only one idea:
我们只有一个想法：
the best solutions need to be simple.
最好的解决方案必须足够简单。
We lost the fear of creating something new.
我们不再害怕创造新的东西。
The path, it's not easy.
这一路走来并不容易。
Many obstacles arise all the time.
我们遇到了很多阻碍。
But we receive strength from our patients.
但我们从患者的身上汲取到了力量。
Their resilience and courage
他们的坚忍与勇气
inspire our creativity.
激励着我们去探索、创造。
Our goal is to make sure
我们的目标是
that no child is left behind, not because of cost or access.
确保没有孩子因为费用和条件的限制而得不到及时的治疗。
So we have to start a foundation
所以我们成立了一个
with a one-to-one model.
一对一模式的基金会。
We will give one device for free
我们为每个患儿免费提供这种器材，
to make sure that every child is treated.
以确保他们都能够得到治疗。
We are in many countries now,
目前这一基金会在很多国家同时运营，
but we need to be everywhere.
但我们需要它进一步扩大至全世界。
This whole thing began with one impossible idea
所有的这些事情都起源于一个几乎不可能的期望，
as will continue it, really:
但我们仍要继续实现它，那就是：
No child is left behind.
让每朵鲜花都有绽放的权力！（不放弃每一个孩子）
Muchas gracias.
非常感谢（西班牙语）。
(Applause)
（掌声）